<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Lawman vs Layman</title>
    <link>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Lawman vs Layman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence Regulation Framework</title>
      <link>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/lawman/artificial-intelligence-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/lawman/artificial-intelligence-regulation/</guid>
      <description>Regulatory landscape Analysis The AI regulatory framework represents a complex intersection of emerging technology governance, risk management principles, and fundamental rights protections. Current regulatory approaches demonstrate significant jurisdictional variations in scope, enforcement mechanisms, and compliance requirements.&#xA;EU AI Act Implementation The European Union&amp;rsquo;s AI Act establishes a risk-based regulatory framework categorizing AI systems across four risk levels:&#xA;Prohibited AI Systems&#xA;Social scoring mechanisms by public authorities Real-time remote biometric identification in public spaces AI systems exploiting vulnerabilities of specific groups Subliminal techniques causing psychological harm High-Risk AI Systems Subject to conformity assessments, CE marking requirements, and ongoing monitoring obligations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence Regulation Framework</title>
      <link>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/layman/artificial-intelligence-regulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/layman/artificial-intelligence-regulation/</guid>
      <description>What Is AI Regulation? AI regulation is like creating rules for how artificial intelligence can be used, similar to how we have traffic laws for driving or food safety rules for restaurants. As AI becomes more powerful and widespread, governments are creating guidelines to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s used safely and fairly.&#xA;Why Do We Need AI Rules? Protecting People from Harm AI systems can sometimes make unfair decisions or mistakes that hurt people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Blockchain Technology</title>
      <link>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/lawman/understanding-blockchain-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/lawman/understanding-blockchain-technology/</guid>
      <description>Technical Overview Blockchain technology represents a paradigm shift in distributed computing, implementing a cryptographically secured, immutable ledger system through consensus mechanisms. The fundamental architecture consists of cryptographically linked blocks containing transaction data, secured through hash functions and digital signatures.&#xA;Cryptographic Foundation The security model relies on SHA-256 hash functions for block integrity and elliptic curve digital signature algorithms (ECDSA) for transaction authentication. Each block contains:&#xA;Merkle Tree Root: Efficiently summarizes all transactions in the block Previous Block Hash: Creates the immutable chain linkage Nonce: Proof-of-work solution for consensus participation Timestamp: Temporal ordering for transaction sequencing Consensus Protocol Analysis Proof of Work (PoW) The original Bitcoin consensus mechanism requires computational work to propose blocks, creating economic incentives aligned with network security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Blockchain Technology</title>
      <link>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/layman/understanding-blockchain-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/layman/understanding-blockchain-technology/</guid>
      <description>What Is Blockchain? Think of blockchain as a digital ledger book that&amp;rsquo;s shared among many people. Instead of one person or company controlling this book, thousands of computers around the world each have an identical copy.&#xA;When someone wants to add a new entry (like a transaction), all these computers must agree it&amp;rsquo;s valid before it gets added. Once something is written in this book, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely difficult to change or erase.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
