<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchain on Lawman vs Layman</title>
    <link>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/tags/blockchain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchain on Lawman vs Layman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Blockchain Technology</title>
      <link>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/lawman/understanding-blockchain-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/lawman/understanding-blockchain-technology/</guid>
      <description>Technical Overview Blockchain technology represents a paradigm shift in distributed computing, implementing a cryptographically secured, immutable ledger system through consensus mechanisms. The fundamental architecture consists of cryptographically linked blocks containing transaction data, secured through hash functions and digital signatures.&#xA;Cryptographic Foundation The security model relies on SHA-256 hash functions for block integrity and elliptic curve digital signature algorithms (ECDSA) for transaction authentication. Each block contains:&#xA;Merkle Tree Root: Efficiently summarizes all transactions in the block Previous Block Hash: Creates the immutable chain linkage Nonce: Proof-of-work solution for consensus participation Timestamp: Temporal ordering for transaction sequencing Consensus Protocol Analysis Proof of Work (PoW) The original Bitcoin consensus mechanism requires computational work to propose blocks, creating economic incentives aligned with network security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Blockchain Technology</title>
      <link>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/layman/understanding-blockchain-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://layman-lawman.netlify.app/layman/understanding-blockchain-technology/</guid>
      <description>What Is Blockchain? Think of blockchain as a digital ledger book that&amp;rsquo;s shared among many people. Instead of one person or company controlling this book, thousands of computers around the world each have an identical copy.&#xA;When someone wants to add a new entry (like a transaction), all these computers must agree it&amp;rsquo;s valid before it gets added. Once something is written in this book, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely difficult to change or erase.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
